<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bloom 🌹</title>
    <link>http://senyosimpson.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bloom 🌹</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://senyosimpson.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data replication in distributed systems</title>
      <link>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/data-replication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/data-replication/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading the book Designing Data-Intensive Applications by Martin Kleppmann. Chapter 5 of the book takes a deep dive into the world of data replication in distributed systems. I have always carried the assumption that data replication is non-trivial but reading the chapter opened my eyes to its true complexity. This post is a summary of the chapter - it can be considered a set of notes. Let&amp;rsquo;s do this 🚀</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grokking gRPC</title>
      <link>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/grokking-grpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/grokking-grpc/</guid>
      <description>If you are similar to me, you&amp;rsquo;ve heard about gRPC countless times but have little idea of what it actually is, what its use cases are and why everyone keeps speaking about it. Initially, I thought it must be another buzzword being thrown around. Fortunately, I was wrong 😆. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a couple of days reading and learning more about it. This blog post is a summary of all I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Just start</title>
      <link>http://senyosimpson.com/essays/just-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://senyosimpson.com/essays/just-start/</guid>
      <description>Having unlimited time to think about yourself and your life for months on end is, and I emphasise, fun. While mostly frustrating, I believe that the Covid-19-induced lockdown has granted us much needed time to critically introspect. Being naturally introspective, I have been in overdrive, reflecting on my shortcomings and my future. Evaluating both critically has yielded some gems. One of them can be summarised into two words, just start. Another way of saying it is, &amp;ldquo;just do it&amp;rdquo; as Nike so fervently reminds us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts I learned from diving into Clojure</title>
      <link>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/clojure-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/clojure-learnings/</guid>
      <description>This year, one of my goals was to learn a functional programming language. I carried this over from last year because who actually achieves their goals, right? To be fair, I did make an attempt - I began learning Haskell. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say, I&amp;rsquo;ll try again one day! Around April this year, on recommendation from one of my mentors, I decided to look into Clojure. It turned out to be a great suggestion and I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying hacking away in Clojure ever since!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning in the wild</title>
      <link>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/machine-learning-in-the-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/machine-learning-in-the-wild/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning promises to be transformational, providing much needed innovation across industries ranging from financial services to healthcare to agriculture. The resurgence of machine learning owing to the astonishing performance of deep learning in computer vision and natural language processing has prompted industry to jump on the bandwagon and utilise machine learning in their businesses. In fact, entire startups are being built around machine learning alone, promising that their new found algorithms will vastly improve and outperform existing products and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned juggling working and studying</title>
      <link>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/working-and-studying/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/working-and-studying/</guid>
      <description>In my final year of undergraduate studies, I had the opportunity to work part-time for Aerobotics ― an agritech startup. With a passion for development, an eagerness to learn and a curiosity for machine learning in the wild, I embraced the opportunity fully, despite having some reservations. How would I manage my final year of undergraduate studies and simultaneously deliver at an acceptable standard at work? As concerned as I was, it turned out to be an exceedingly positive and rewarding experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://senyosimpson.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://senyosimpson.com/about/</guid>
      <description>Wagwan, I&amp;rsquo;m Senyo! I am a 23 year old machine learning engineer residing in the beautiful city of Cape Town, South Africa. I work at Aerobotics where we are building the next generation of smart technology in the agriculture industry. From an academic standpoint, my interests lie in statistical machine learning. Topics such as probabilisitic generative modeling, approximate inference, density estimation and the likes are fascinating and the theory is beautiful to say the least (if only I understood it properly 😆).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://senyosimpson.com/philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://senyosimpson.com/philosophy/</guid>
      <description>An enumeration of my core philosophy with respect to my career. This is more for documentation purposes than anything but I think some people may find it useful hence I am sharing it openly.
Stay lean Staying lean means purposefully staying focused on a small set of topics and extracting maximum value from them.
As with most people who are passionate about the work they do, I have about 1000 side projects and ideas I want to spend time on.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>