<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Bloom</title>
    <link>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Bloom</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://senyosimpson.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Concepts I learned from diving into Clojure</title>
      <link>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/clojure-learnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/clojure-learnings/</guid>
      <description>This year, one of my goals was to learn a functional programming language. I carried this over from last year because who actually achieves their goals, right? To be fair, I did make an attempt - I began learning Haskell. Let&amp;rsquo;s just say, I&amp;rsquo;ll try again one day! Around April this year, on recommendation from one of my mentors, I decided to look into Clojure. It turned out to be a great suggestion and I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying hacking away in Clojure ever since!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning in the wild</title>
      <link>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/machine-learning-in-the-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/machine-learning-in-the-wild/</guid>
      <description>Machine learning promises to be transformational, providing much needed innovation across industries ranging from financial services to healthcare to agriculture. The resurgence of machine learning owing to the astonishing performance of deep learning in computer vision and natural language processing has prompted industry to jump on the bandwagon and utilise machine learning in their businesses. In fact, entire startups are being built around machine learning alone, promising that their new found algorithms will vastly improve and outperform existing products and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned juggling working and studying</title>
      <link>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/working-and-studying/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://senyosimpson.com/posts/working-and-studying/</guid>
      <description>In my final year of undergraduate studies, I had the opportunity to work part-time for Aerobotics ― an agritech startup. With a passion for development, an eagerness to learn and a curiosity for machine learning in the wild, I embraced the opportunity fully, despite having some reservations. How would I manage my final year of undergraduate studies and simultaneously deliver at an acceptable standard at work? As concerned as I was, it turned out to be an exceedingly positive and rewarding experience.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>